Finding Aid for George Romney Papers 1920s-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  - Motion Picture Films
    - L3-8-6-69, Romney fiscal meetings clip August 1963, 852178_5-67
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-67, flv
    - L3-8-15-2, Romney clip August 1963, 852178_5-68
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:38
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-68, flv
    - L3-10-23-55, Griffin-Romney tax plan clip October 1963, 852178_5-69
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:23
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-69, flv
    - L3-10-25-62, John Martin-Romney tax referral clip October 1963, 852178_5-70
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-70, flv
    - 1968 Detroit Olympics bid clip, October 1963, 852178_5-71
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:21
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-71, flv
    - Romney and Jerome Cavanagh clip, concerning holding 1964 political conventions in Detroit, 1963, 852178_5-72
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:02:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-72, flv
    - L4-11-22-105, Romney-Staebler debate clip November 1964, 852178_5-73-1
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:02:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-73-1, flv
    - L4-11-22-105, Romney-Staebler debate clip November 1964, 852178_5-74-2
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:03:26
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-74-2, flv
    - "Don't curse the darkness: a look at youth crime in Michigan" 1964, 852178_5-75
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:28:53
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-75, flv
    - Re-elect George Romney clip, by Dwight Eisenhower 1964, 852178_5-76
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-76, flv
    - "Explosion of new jobs": Tecumseh ground-breaking ceremony clip 1964, 852178_5-77
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, silent, 00:00:15
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-77, flv
    - "On the move" (highlights of Michigan's growth) August 1965, 852178_5-78
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:28:25
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-78, flv
    - "To your good health" (history of health care in Michigan, Romney speaks) October 28, 1965, 852178_5-79
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:28:35
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-79, flv
    - L6-4-7-82, Livingston-governor clip April 1966, 852178_5-80
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:26
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-80, flv
    - L6-4-15-150, Civil rights clip April 4, 1966, 852178_5-81
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-81, flv
    - L6-4-19-167, Ferency clip April 1966, 852178_5-82
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:18
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-82, flv
    - L6-7-12-145, Romney birthday clip July 1966, 852178_5-83
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:51
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-83, flv
    - L6-8-9-135, Education meeting clip (Cavanagh-Romney) August 1966, 852178_5-84
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:23
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-84, flv
    - L6-8-23-51, Employees strike clip August 1966, 852178_5-85
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:55
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-85, flv
    - L6-8-30-91, Right wing clip August 1966, 852178_5-86
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-86, flv
    - L6-9-31-80, Benton Harbor riots clip September 1966, 852178_5-87
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:26
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-87, flv
    - L6-10-4-119, Romney-Ferency Economic Club clip October 1966, 852178_5-88
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:03
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-88, flv
    - L6-10-22-56, Increased car prices clip October 1966, 852178_5-89
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:21
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-89, flv
    - "Know your action team" (Romney, Milliken, Griffin, their wives, and other Republican candidates address the voters) November 1966, 852178_5-90
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:28:15
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-90, flv
    - L6-11-31-144, Lou Harris pollster on Romney clip November 1966, 852178_5-91
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:48
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-91, flv
    - L6-12-9-14, Romney post-election conference clip December 1966, 852178_5-92
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:51
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-92, flv
    - L6-13-6-12, Holloway-Romney volunteers '68 clip December 1966, 852178_5-93
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:33
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-93, flv
    - L6-13-14-58, Politics-Goldwater clip December 1966, 852178_5-94
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:21
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-94, flv
    - L6-13-22-105, Christmas message clip December 1966, 852178_5-95
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:51
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 7)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-95, flv
    - L6-13-23, Greets shoppers clip December 1966, 852178_5-96
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:45
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-96, flv
    - Romney-Griffin spots (22 commercials, also includes spots for George Washington and Larry Lindemer) 1966, 852178_5-97
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:22:40
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-97, flv
    - Romney-Williams debate clip (no debate footage) 1966, 852178_5-98
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:02:29
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-98, flv
    - Robert Griffin campaign spot 1966, 852178_5-99
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:26
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-99, flv
    - L7-1-5-22, Trips outside Michigan clip January 1967, 852178_5-100
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:21
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-100, flv
    - L7-1-12-58, State of state edited footage January 1967, 852178_5-101
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:04:21
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-101, flv
    - L7-2-2-21, Man on street-Romney fiscal proposals clip February 1967, 852178_5-102
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-102, flv
    - L7-2-3-29, Stockmeyer-Romney fiscal plan clip February 1967, 852178_5-103
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:55
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-103, flv
    - L7-2-9-76, Medicaid clip February 1967, 852178_5-104
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:20
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-104, flv
    - L7-2-17-107, Western campaign clip February 1967, 852178_5-105
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:20
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-105, flv
    - L7-2-19-122, Alaska clip February 1967, 852178_5-106
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, silent, 00:00:38
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-106, flv
    - Alaska trip edited footage February 1967, 852178_5-107
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, optical, 00:15:31
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-107, flv
    - L7-2-24-153, Vietnam clip February 1967, 852178_5-108
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:45
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-108, flv
    - L7-4-8-90, Hartford speech clip April 7, 1967, 852178_5-109
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:33
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-109, flv
    - "Vietnam speech, April 7, Hartford, Conn." (actually edited footage of campaigning in New Hampshire, text of Vietnam speech enclosed) April 7, 1967, 852178_5-110
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:28:55
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-110, flv
    - L7-4-14-128, Austerity budget clip April 1967, 852178_5-111
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:43
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-111, flv
    - L7-4-14-129, William F. Buckley-Romney politics clip April 7, 1967, 852178_5-112
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:28
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-112, flv
    - L7-5-8-95, Fiscal reform clip May 1967, 852178_5-113
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:51
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-113, flv
    - L7-5-11-121, Religion clip May 1967, 852178_5-114
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:36
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-114, flv
    - L7-5-18-181, Income tax passed clip May 1967, 852178_5-115
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:01
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-115, flv
    - L7-5-20-202, Romney-Waldron politics clip May 1967, 852178_5-116
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:38
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-116, flv
    - L7-5-21-205, Japanese governor clip May 1967, 852178_5-117
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, silent, 00:00:18
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-117, flv
    - L7-5-27-27, Tax reform clip May 1967, 852178_5-118
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:00:41
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-118, flv
    - Address to National Conference of Editorial Writers, Nashville, Tenn., footage (October 6, Romney speaks of his recent tour of American cities; transcript included), 1967-10-06, 852178_5-119
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, optical, 00:33:06
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-119, flv
    - Nashville question period footage October 6, 1967, 852178_5-120
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, optical, 00:05:46
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-120, flv
    - Schools, taxes, etc. 1967, 852178_5-121
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:13
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-121, flv
    - "Lenore" (1970 campaign film for Lenore Romney) 1970, 852178_5-122
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, optical, 00:26:58
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-122, flv
    - Campaign speeches footage undated, 852178_5-123
      (undated)
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:10:40
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-123, flv
    - "Michigan" (Michigan Tourist Council foreign tourist film) undated, 852178_5-124
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, optical, 00:02:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-124, flv
    - Romney speaks on talks with Wolfson (American Motors) undated, 852178_5-125
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:35
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 8)
      - Streaming File: 852178_5-125, flv
  - Filmstrip
    The final series consists of a single Filmstrip.
    - "George Romney: a portrait of leadership" [35 mm] (Box 9-V)
- Sound Recordings
  The Romney audiotape collection consists of 759 reel-to-reel and cassette sound tapes made in the period 1952-1969. Included are tapes of Romney speeches, press conferences, and political addresses and meetings. The collection also includes tapes made by the Romney staff of speeches and interviews of other political figures. The bulk of these tapes will be found in Romney's Gubernatorial Series with a smaller quantity (ca. 149 tapes) located in the Pre-Gubernatorial Subgroup.
  To facilitate economy in storage, the tapes have been arranged by size and then chronologically. The seven-inch tapes, which comprise the bulk of the collection, include a separate subseries of audiotapes of press conferences. Although the chronological series of audiotapes includes many Romney press conferences, this subseries consists of tapes, many of which cover multiple dates. To avoid confusion in the chronological listing of tapes, therefore, it was decided to maintain these multiple date press conferences as a separate unit. For the researcher interested in listening to a specifically dated Romney press conference, he/she should first consult the chronological listing, then the listing for the multiple-dated press conferences.
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - Chronological Series I, 7 inch reel-to-reel audiotapes
    - 1952
      - GR speech, Society of Automotive Engineers, Chicago December 3, 1952, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1953
      - GR speech, S-A-E meeting December 8, 1953, 3 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1954
      - GR speech, Town Hall, Dearborn October 4, 1954, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR press conference, Detroit October 14, 1954, 2 tapes 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR interview, Atlantic City November 8, 1954, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR press conference, Nash, Kansas City November 15, 1954, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Mason Tributes for Detroit Roundtable November 18, 1954, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Chicago All American Motors Show December 2, 1954, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Hotel Astor, New York City December 13, 1954, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1955
      - GR press conference, Statler Hotel, Washington, D.C. January 4, 1955, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, First Annual Employee Preview, Milwaukee Arena October 8, 1955, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Browns Lake Resort, Burlinton, Wisconsin October 11, 1955, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Detroit Society of Security Analysts, Hotel Fort Shelby, Detroit December 7, 1955, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1956
      - GR speech, Utah Manufacturers January 27, 1956, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - George Romney press conference, American Motors “Progress Report,” Statler Hotel, 1956 April 24, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
        - [Part 1], [852178-SR-20-1]; mp3 file; (Discussing the merger of Nash-Kelvinator and Hudson motors and the relationship with American Motors.)
      - GR speech, U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C. May 2, 1956, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Cranbrook graduating class June 1956, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, second Annual Employees Product preview, Lakefront Stadium, Kenosha, Wisconsin September 14, 1956, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1957
      - GR press conference, Cadillac, Michigan March 21, 1957, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - George Romney press conference, Statler Hotel, Detroit, 1957 April 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
        - [Part 1], [852178-SR-25-1]; mp3 file; (Box mentions "Wilson" as does Romney during opening speech report on the achievements of American Motors Corporation.)
      - GR speech, Milwaukee Preview September 14, 1957, 2 tapes 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Chicago Dealer Meeting September 27, 1957, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR press conference, Orchard Lake Country Club October 2, 1957, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Rambler Auto Show November 9, 1957, 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, Detroit Employee Meeting November 15, 1957, 2 tapes 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR press conference, Statler Hotel, Detroit December 18, 1957, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
    - 1958
      - GR speech, Auto Buy Rally - Cleveland Auto Dealers March 14, 1958, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR speech, North Carolina Dealers Association, Pinehurst, North Carolina April 29, 1958, 3-3/4 ips (Box 16-E)
      - GR interview, Transatlantic BBC broadcast, Detroit May 6, 1958, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Akron United Fund Dinner July 6, 1958, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Brown's Lake, Wisconsin September 10, 1958, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Employee Preview, Milwaukee September 13, 1958, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, University of Michigan Convocation, Ann Arbor September 18, 1958, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Dealer Speech, Oakland, California September 29, 1958, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Kelvinator Convention Luncheon, Grand Rapids, Michigan October 6, 1958, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, American Petroleum Institute, Chicago November 9, 1958, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Harvard Business School, Cambridge, Massachusetts November 19, 1958, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, New York Security Analysis December 16, 1958, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
    - 1959
      - GR speech, Adcraft Club of Detroit January 30, 1959, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Federal Business Association of Detroit February 24, 1959, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR interview, Marshall Berges, Detroit bureau manager for Time Magazine March 11, 1959, 3 tapes 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Grand Rapids Employee talk October 22, 1959, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Romney Meeting, Detroit October 23, 1959, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Security Analysts Meeting, Kenosha, Wisconsin November 18, 1959, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Acceptance of the Vermilyn Medal, Franklin Institute, Philadelphia November 18, 1959, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Economic Club, Chicago December 15, 1959, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
    - 1960
      - GR speech, Citizens for Michigan Regional Meeting, Alpena, Michigan January 6, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Northern States Power Sales Conference January 11, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, "Where's Rambler Going," Security Analysts Talk January 18, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR interview, Stephens College American Government Class January 22, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Town Hall, Vet's Memorial Building January 26, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Michigan League, Ann Arbor January 28, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR press conference, Michigan Union, Ann Arbor January 28, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, ASSA, Atlantic City February 15, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, Michigan Education Association, rep. assembly, Lansing, Michigan April 1, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR press conference, Lansing, Michigan April 1, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17-E)
      - GR speech, McGraw-Hill Group, Atlantic City April 8, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Milwaukee Press Club Gridiron Dinner April 19, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Town Hall, Dearborn Inn May 3, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Milwaukee YMCA Annual Meeting May 5, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Racine Chamber of Commerce May 5, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Journalism Institute - University of Wisconsin, Madison May 6, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Chamber of Commerce, Waukesha, Wisconsin May 6, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, University of Utah Alumni Association Meeting, Los Angeles May 23, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, National Association of Purchasing Agents, Los Angeles May 23, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR press conference, New York June 15, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, General Federation of Women's Clubs, Washington, D.C. June 16, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Kiwanis International Convention, Miami Beach, Florida June 30, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, American Motors Luncheon, Chicago August 24, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, United States National Student Association, Minneapolis, Minnesota August 29, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Employee's 6th Annual Jamboree, Milwaukee Stadium September 3, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Grand Rapids Employee Talk September 6, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Los Angeles Dealer Meeting September 9, 1960, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, National Securities Traders Association, Sun Valley, Idaho September 11, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Michigan State University. Oakland United Foundation September 14, 1960 (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Cincinnati Dealer Meeting September 15, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Miami Dealer Meeting September 20, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Michigan Municipal League September 22, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Chamber of Commerce, Hartford September 26, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Chamber of Commerce, Dearborn October 11, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, National Industrial Conference Board, Toronto October 13, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR interview, Gil Christie, Toronto, Ontario October 13, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR press conference, Sheraton Cadillac Hotel, Detroit, Michigan October 14, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Detroit Salary Bonus group October 25, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, American Society of Industrial Designers Conference, Chicago October 27, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, International Association of Ice Cream Manufacturers, Chicago October 31, 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech December 1960, 3-3/4 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR speech, Executive Employees of American Motors Corps. December 2, 1960, 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
      - GR press conference December 15, 1960, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 18-E)
    - 1961
      - GR speech, Honolulu Chamber of Commerce January 5, 1961, 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Crystal, American Bankers Association, Ballroom January 23, 1961, 3-3/4 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Empire Club of Canada January 26, 1961, 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Stockholder Meeting February 1, 1961, 3 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Farm Management Banquet, Lansing, Michigan February 2, 1961, 2 tapes 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Secondary School Principals Cobo Hall, Detroit February 11, 1961, 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR interview, Al La Guire of WKAR, Lansing, Michigan February 15, 1961, 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Battle Creek, Michigan February 24, 1961, 3-3/4 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, C.F.M., Grand Rapids February 27, 1961, 7-1/2 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Ann Arbor Roundtable of Christians and Jews March 4, 1961, 3-3/4 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Grosse Pointe High School, C.F.M. March 6, 1961, 3-3/4 ips (Box 19-E)
      - GR speech, Kenosha Employees March 17, 1961, 3-3/4 ips (Box 19-E)